genworth.com 2019-12-08

# Online Privacy Policy

## 

This Web site is operated by Genworth Financial, Inc., and its affiliated companies1 (“We”), and this Privacy Policy applies to this website.

Federal and state laws require that we tell you how we collect, use, share, and protect your personal information. Those laws also limit how we may use your personal information and how we may share it with others. Protecting the privacy and security of your personal information is very important to us. Please read this notice carefully. It will help you understand what we do with the personal information we collect both online and offline.

## 

You do not need to register to use most of our websites. If you do not register, we do not collect any personal information about you. We may, however, collect anonymous information about your visit to our websites for security and internal operations purposes. This may include your IP address, browser type, the website you came from, and your likely country of origin. We may also measure data like how often users go to a specific page, how long they spend on that page and similar information. This anonymous information is aggregated and is not associated with individual users. It is collected to help us analyze usage patterns and improve our site’s overall performance.

If you want us to contact you to provide you with information or to provide answers to your questions, you must provide minimal personal information. In most cases, we will ask only for your name, address, telephone number, or email address.

To access information about your existing insurance policies or accounts and for some other purposes, you must register. When you register, we will ask for more personal information. That may include your policy or account number, your date of birth and your social security number.

## 

We may share your personal information, but only if the law allows us to do so, with other Genworth companies for marketing purposes.

We may make additional disclosures of information as permitted or required by law. For example, we may disclose information to government agencies including law enforcement agencies or state insurance authorities, businesses, or individuals in response to court orders, subpoenas, or to resolve complaints.

## 

When you contact us:

  * To ask for general information
  * To apply for a new policy
  * To create an account so you can view information about your existing policy

When we contact you:

  * To service your policy
  * To provide information you ask for
  * To provide information we believe you may be interested in

When we contact others:

  * To obtain or confirm information about you (e.g. medical records)

## 

Within Genworth:

  * To service your policy
  * To answer your requests for information

Outside of Genworth:

  * We provide information to government agencies, businesses, or individuals in response to court orders, subpoenas, or to resolve complaints.
  * We use third-party services on our websites to help in communicating or interacting with you and members of the general public.
  * If you pay premiums online to process your payment.
  * We may disclose personal information as permitted or required by law. For example, we may disclose personal information to law enforcement agencies or state insurance authorities.

## 

  * Some personal information you may change yourself by logging into your account. This includes information like your address and your banking information.
  * If you see other information that is not correct, you may call the number on your policy statement or may write to the address on that statement. Or, you may call 888 GENWORTH (888.436.9678).

## 

When you provide information to us on our websites, we use encryption and authentication tools to protect that information after it gets to us. Please note, however, that no internet data transmission between your computer and our systems is completely secure. While we endeavor to protect your personal information, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information before it gets to us; you transmit that information at your own risk. If you are uncomfortable providing information over the internet, you may be able to mail it or fax it to us.

Once we receive your information, we use procedures and technologies designed to prevent unauthorized access to your personal information and to protect against the loss, misuse, and alteration of information under our control. We maintain physical, electronic, and procedural protections to protect personal information in accordance with applicable standards.

We require that third parties who have access to your personal information implement similar standards. We require third parties to agree to keep your personal information confidential.

We restrict access to personal information to employees and third parties who have a legitimate business need in providing products or services to you. Employees who violate our privacy policy are subject to disciplinary action. Third parties who violate our privacy policy are subject to having their contract terminated.

If you want to provide us with highly confidential information, such as a credit card number, you may want to call us or send it by regular mail or by fax. Emails sent from outside of our website may not be protected. We will never ask for personal information via email.

The servers hosting our systems are in the United States. If you access our websites from outside the United States, this means that information you provide may be transferred to and hosted on servers in the United States. By submitting information to us, you expressly consent to those transfers.

## 

A cookie is information saved by your web browser. When you visit a website, the site may place a cookie on your web browser so it can recognize your device in the future. If you return to that site later, it can read that cookie to remember you from your last visit and keep track of you over time.

  * collect information about the pages you view and your activities on the site
  * enable the site to recognize you, for example by:  
– remembering your user ID  
– keeping track of your preferences if you visit the website again
  * customize your browsing experience

The cookie transmits this information back to the website’s computer (or server). You can set your web browser to warn you about attempts to place cookies on your computer or to limit the type of cookies you allow. For more information, please see the [FTC's guidance on cookies and other forms of online tracking.opens in new window](https://www.consumer.ftc.gov/articles/0042-online-tracking)

This website uses first party HTTPS both session/persistent cookies for different use cases. For Analytics, this website uses third party cookies as well.

## 

At this time, our websites do not respond to browser Do Not Track (DNT) signals or similar mechanisms. We do not collect personally identifiable information about you using DNT signals as you move across other sites or services. Nor do we allow other companies to place DNT signals on our website. No user personal information is shared with network advertisers or stored by the cookie.

## 

We do not knowingly solicit information from children and we do not intentionally market our products or services to children. You may choose to have a child insured, be owner or be a beneficiary to one of our products. If we learn that we have inadvertently received personal information from a child who has visited this website, we will delete that information from our records.

## 

The effective date of this privacy policy is September 1, 2017. This replaces all previous online privacy policies. We may change this privacy policy at any time. If we make material changes, we will post the changes on this website.

## 

You may find links to other websites on our websites. We are not responsible for the information collection practices of those other websites. We cannot guarantee how those parties use cookies or whether they use cookies that may identify you personally. You should carefully review the privacy policies of each website you visit to understand how they collect, use, and disclose personal information.

## 

  * Genworth Privacy Notice
  * Privacy Notice FAQ
  * Genworth HIPAA Privacy Policy (Health Information)

In compliance with the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (HIPAA), we protect health information as described in our Notice of Privacy Practices.

You may obtain a copy of the revised notice by clicking here or by writing to us at Genworth Life, Privacy Compliance, P.O. Box 40005, Lynchburg, VA 24506.

  * [Disclosure - Confidentiality for Victims of Domestic Violence](https://pro.genworth.com/riiproweb/productinfo/pdf/165046.pdf)

## 

Write to Genworth’s Privacy Compliance Office:  
Genworth Financial  
Privacy Compliance Office  
P.O. Box 40005  
Lynchburg, VA 24506  

## 

Visit [ftc.gov/idtheftopens in new window](https://www.consumer.ftc.gov/features/feature-0014-identity-theft) to learn about the crime of identity theft, including detailed information to help you prevent, detect, and defend against it.

Visit [OnGuardOnlineopens in new window](https://www.consumer.ftc.gov/features/feature-0038-onguardonline) to learn how to be on guard against internet fraud, secure your computer, and protect your personal information.
